backstage.com 2018-06-24

# Privacy Policy

Your privacy is important to us. The Backstage Privacy Policy describes what data we collect from you, the purpose for collecting the data in conjunction with the Backstage Sites and Services, how we share, process, and manage your Personal Data, and your rights associated with your data.

This Privacy Policy applies to www.backstage.com, www.auditionupdate.com and the Backstage IOS App (together, "Backstage"). It explains how we collect information from users of Backstage, and how we use such information. Your use of Backstage constitutes your acceptance of this Privacy Policy. Please also read our Terms of Use, which govern the basic operation of Backstage. If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Policy or the Terms of Use, you should immediately stop using or visiting Backstage.

 **1\. The Information We Collect and Use**

 **2\. Examples of How Backstage Uses Your Data**

* To create an account for you to use the Backstage casting platform and services. 

* To personalize Backstage to give you a better experience, such as sending you targeted job postings based on your location.

* To respond to your requests or to manage user accounts.

* To receive product feedback and understand our users better in order to improve Backstage.

* To monitor the safety and security of the Backstage service and casting platform.

* To use data and content about users for communications promoting membership, job posting, and engagement with Backstage, on Backstage properties and across other platforms.

* To target and measure the performance of advertisements displayed to our users directly by Backstage or through third party advertising partners, on and off Backstage.

Backstage may disclose your Personally Identifiable Information to third parties in connection with a corporate transaction where all or a portion of our business (e.g., a portion that includes our customer lists) is sold or transferred. We also may disclose your Personally Identifiable Information if disclosure is required by law or as part of a lawsuit or government investigation or proceeding, or in order to permit us to exercise or preserve our legal rights or take action regarding potentially illegal activities or to protect the safety of any person.

Backstage reserves the right, but has no obligation, to monitor information, comments or other content that you voluntarily disclose and post to the Websites. Backstage reserves the right to remove any such information or material for any reason or no reason, including without limitation, if in our sole opinion such information or material violates, or may violate, any applicable law or the Terms of Use or to protect or defend our rights or property or those of any third party. Backstage also reserves the right to remove information upon the request of any third party.

Backstage reserves the right to investigate abuses on the Websites and enforce and apply this Privacy Policy, the Terms of Use and any other terms or conditions applicable to the Websites or the use thereof. Backstage may disclose information about you to third parties if we have a good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to (1) take action regarding suspected illegal activities; (2) enforce or apply the Terms of Use; (3) comply with legal process and law enforcement instructions and orders, such as a search warrant, subpoena, statute, judicial proceeding or other legal process served on us; (4) protect our rights, reputation, and property or that of our users or the public or (5) protect against legal liability.

**3\. How Backstage shares information**

Talent Profile

You may choose to make your talent profile fully visible to all users on and Backstage, as well as publicly discoverable across the world wide web, or not publicly discoverable, where only logged in users can view it. You may modify the information you have provided to Backstage at any time through your Backstage profile.

Messaging

The Backstage service allows you to share information with other users by sending and receiving messages on the Backstage messaging system. When you send email or message Backstage customer support, Backstage will collect and store your name, email address and the content of your message so we can provide customer support.

Participating in Backstage Community Forums

When you post messages on the message boards on Backstage, the information contained in your posting will be stored on Backstage servers and will be openly available by other Backstage users and across the world wide web.

Posting Casting Notices

When a user posts a casting notice, the notice may contain personally identifiable information. By posting a casting notice on Backstage, you consent to share the contents of the casting notice with other Backstage users, as well as make the contents of your casting notice publicly discoverable across the world wide web.

Other Parties Designated by You

When using the Backstage Service, you may share your data with other parties designated by you. For example, when applying to a casting notice on Backstage, you may share personally identifiable data with the recipient of your application. When inviting a Backstage user to apply to your casting notice, you may also share personally identifiable information with that user.

Service Providers

From time to time, we may partner with unaffiliated companies or individuals for market research, product development, quality assurance testing, or similar purposes. These companies or individuals may be provided with access to personally identifiable information, but we will require by contract that they agree to maintain the confidentiality, security and integrity of such information. We also may subcontract with other companies and individuals to do work on our behalf; they may be provided with access to personally identifiable information, but only as needed to perform their functions.

Data Processors

Backstage, as a data controller, collects and shares data with different data processors in the following categories:

Technology and Infrastructure: Backstage distributes data to processors in order to host, enable and support the Backstage platform and service.

Analytics and Reporting: Backstage distributes data to analytics platforms to better understand user behavior and track key business metrics, in order to provide a better service to its users.

Marketing Partners: Backstage distributes data to marketing companies to facilitate email marketing, IOS app messaging campaigns, on-site promotions, and social media, search, and display advertising campaigns.

International Data Transfers

Information, including information collected in the European Economic Area ("EEA") may be transferred, stored and processed by Backstage and its services providers in the United States and other countries whose data protection laws may be different than the laws of your country. We will protect your Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Notice wherever it is processed and take appropriate steps to protect the information in accordance with applicable laws.

**4\. Children Under 13**

The Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 and its rules (collectively, "COPPA") require us to inform parents and legal guardians (as used in this, "parents") about our practices for collecting, using, and disclosing personal information from children under the age of 13 ("children"). It also requires us to obtain verifiable consent from a child's parent for certain collection, use, and disclosure of the child's personal information.

This section notifies parents that (i) the types of information we may collect from children, (ii) how we use the information we collect, and (iii) our practices for disclosing that information is consistent with the other sections of this Privacy Policy.

This section also notifies parents of (i) our practices for notifying and obtaining parents' consent when we collect personal information from children, including how a parent may revoke consent and (ii) all operators that collect or maintain information from children through Websites.

This section only applies to children under the age of 13 and supplements the other provisions of this Privacy Policy. Only the other provisions of this Privacy Policy applies to teens and adults.

Parental Consent

Only a Parent or Legal Guardian of a child under the age of 13 years old may create an account on Backstage.com to promote their child’s performing arts career. When creating a Backstage Actor Profile on behalf of their child, the Parent or Legal Guardian will be asked to enter their child’s date of birth. If the child is under 13 years of age,a Parent must affirm that they are the Parent or Legal Guadian of the Child whose profile they are creating, and consents to the release of the child’s personal information within the Backstage Actor Profile.

Accessing And Correcting Your Child's Personal Information

At any time, you may review the child's personal information maintained by us, require us to correct or delete the personal information, and/or refuse to permit us from further collecting or using the child's information.

You can review, change, or delete your child's personal information by:

Logging into your Backstage account and visiting your child’s account profile page.

Sending us an email to customers@backstage.com. To protect your privacy and security, we may require you to take certain steps or provide additional information to verify your identity before we provide any information or make corrections

Operators That Collect or Maintain Information from Children

A list of all operators or processors that may collect or maintain personal information from children through the Websites is available here.

Please direct your inquiries about any operator's privacy practices and use of children's information to the operator at its contact information provided.

Notwithstanding the foregoing, only the Parent or Legal Guardian of a child under the age of 16 years old who is a resident in a country within the European Economic Area (“EEA”) may create an account on Backstage.com to manager their child’s performing arts career. When creating a Backstage Actor Profile on behalf of their child, the Parent or Legal Guardian will be asked to enter their child’s date of birth. If the child is under 16 years of age, a Parent must affirm that they are the Parent or Legal Guardian of the Child whose profile they are creating, and consents to the release of the child’s personal information within the Backstage Actor Profile. Children who live in EEA countries under the age of 16 are prohibited from using Backstage.

**5\. Data Retention**

Backstage retains personally identifiable information for the maximum period allowable by law, where there is a reasonable business need or legitimate interest to retain such data. You may contact us at customers@backstage.com if at any time you would like to see the Personally Identifiable Information we hold about you, or to ask us to correct or update this information, or to ask us to delete it. Please contact us if you have questions or wish to take any action with respect to information to which this Privacy Policy applies (see below for contact information).

**6\. Additional Rights, Rules, And Provisions For European Economic Area Users**

If you are the resident of a country in the EEA, you may have additional privacy rights available to you under applicable laws. We will process your requests in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

  * Right not to provide or withdraw consent: you have the right not to provide or withdraw your consent at any time.

  * Right of access: you may have the right to access the Personal Data that you provided Us.

  * Right of erasure: you may have the right to the erasure of Personal Data that we hold about you.

  * Right to object to processing: you may have the right to request that Backstage stop processing your Personal Data and/or to stop sending you marketing communications.

  * Right to rectification: you may have the right to require Backstage to correct any of your Personal Data.

  * The right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority if you feel the above conditions aren’t being met.

To make such requests regarding your personal data, please email the customer success team at customers@backstage.com with the term “privacy” in the subject line. Please contact us if you have questions or wish to take any action with respect to information to which this Privacy Policy applies (see below for contact information).

Backstage is a casting service for film, television, theatre, commercials and other performing arts productions. Users located in EEA countries may choose to enter personal data relating to their race or ethnicity, trade union membership, gender and sexual orientation when using the service. This type of information is considered to be a part of the “Special Categories of Personal Data” under Article 9 of the GDPR. By choosing to enter the above categories of personal data on the Backstage service, you are giving explicit consent to the processing of this personal data for purposes referenced in this privacy policy on Backstage. 

Backstage has appointed a Data Protection Officer to oversee all aspects of our privacy and data security policies. If you would like to contact our Data Protection Officer, please send an email to DPO@backstage.com.

In order for users from EEA countries to use Backstage websites, users must accept cookies. Users will be prompted at the beginning of their session to accept cookies. Users may withdraw consent by deleting their cookies from their browser settings at any time. 

**7\. Links to other Websites**

This Privacy Policy applies only to the Websites. The Websites may contain links to other websites that Backstage may not own or operate. The links from the Websites do not imply that Backstage endorses or has reviewed these websites. The policies and procedures we describe here do not apply to these websites. We neither can control nor are responsible for the privacy practices or content of these websites. We suggest contacting these websites directly for information on their privacy policies.

**8\. Your California Privacy Rights**

California Civil Code Section §1798.83 permits users of Websites that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to customers@backstage.com.

**9\. Security of Your Data**

Backstage is committed to protecting the security of Your Personal Data. We use a variety of industry-standard security technologies and procedures to help protect Your personal data from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. We attempt to follow policies and procedures that will protect against unauthorized access to your personally identifiable information. No amount of measures is 100% secure, however. We cannot make any promises or guarantees that your data will be safe, and you provide information to us at your own risk.

**10\. How To Contact Us**

You may contact Backstage LLC regarding our privacy practices at the following address:

Backstage LLC 45 Main St. STE 416 Brooklyn, NY 11201 customers@backstage.com 917-725-6367 

**11\. Changes To The Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy is effective as of May 22nd, 2018. Backstage reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. Backstage does not undertake to provide you with personal notice of any changes. In the event of material changes, Backstage will provide notice by means that are reasonable under the circumstances, such as by posting a notice on the websites. Your continued use of Backstage following the posting of changes to this Privacy Policy means you accept those changes.
